Sivakumar M

Chandrasivakumar1992@gmail.com

India Phone No: +91 74186 79098 Text Now Phone No: 914 222 0051

Summary:

Overall 5+ years of experience and 3.5 years' experience in recruiting process in both IT and Non-IT requirements for US and Canada based companies. Deals with both contract and fulltime job positions. Screening resumes based on the job description, short-listing potential candidates, conducting initial screening, negotiating salary, conducting reference checks, follow ups with candidate's post joining. Excellent communication skill in written and verbal.

Technical Skills:

- Recruiting
- Communication skills
- Microsoft Office, Outlook, LinkedIn
- Job Diva, Ceipal
- Monster, CB, Dice
- Human resources

Education Details:

MSc CS - Bharathidasan University - Tiruchchirappalli, Tamil Nadu - 2015 BSc CS - Bharathidasan University - Tiruchchirappalli, Tamil Nadu - 2013

Work Experience:

US IT Technical Recruiter

Scalable Systems

December 2022 to September 2023

- Extensive experience in working with all kind of US and Canada based IT positions ranging from Developers to manager level positions.
- Strong experience on ATS (Ceipal, LinkedIn) for posting, tracking, updating and maintaining all requisitions.
- Sourced, qualified and conducted screening interviews with job candidates.
- Strong understanding of Corp-to-Corp, W2, US Citizens, Green Card Holder, H1B, EAD and Implementation/Direct client relationships. Experience with Full Time Employment (FTE), Contractual (C2C) & Contract to Hire Positions. Excellent knowledge of Microsoft office, MS Outlook, Skype.
- Good Negotiation and Closure skills with strong emphasis on Client/Candidate. Very good experience in placing consultants with very good margins/spreads. Good experience in gathering consultants for the requirements.
- Was involved in following up the candidate continuously and maintaining the good relationship with the candidates and getting them on board.
- Possess excellent knowledge of recruiting and sourcing, preliminary interviewing, reference checking, rate/ salary negotiations. And Have experience in dealing with all of kind of authorization (US Citizens, GC, EAD, HIB etc.) Hands on experience in contract, Permanent, Contract to Hire positions.
- Short listing candidates according to the skills, experience, rate, location etc. Strong negotiation skills.
- Extensive experience in working with all kind of US and Canada based IT positions ranging from Developers to manager level positions, Scheduling candidates for fact to face/telephonic interview events, establishing close contact with candidates to ensure participation in interview events.
- Extensive experience in job portals (i.e.: Monster.com, career Builder, Dice.com, Indeed, zip recruiter and LinkedIn, Etc.), Solid understanding of recruitment at all levels (technical & non-technical).
- A resourceful, solution-focused professional with excellent interpersonal and rapport-building skills.
- Management of the complete recruitment life-cycle for sourcing the best talent from diverse sources after identification of manpower requirements. Extensive hands on experience in various sourcing tactics such as cold calling, job boards, networking, etc. to ensure a diverse pipeline of candidates

US IT Technical Recruiter

IDC Technologies

August 2021 to September 2022

- Responsible for implementing full life cycle of recruitment from sourcing, pre-screening, interviewing, presenting and closing offers.
- Searching and identifying potential candidates from online portals (Job Diva, Ceipal, Career Builder, Monster, Dice), LinkedIn.
- Work experience on IT requirements for Implementation Partners (Tech Mahindra, Infosys, TCS, HCL, CTS) and IT/Non-IT requirements
- Using knowledge of full-life cycle recruiting including, but not limited to sourcing, screening, qualifying, interviewing and candidate relationship management while providing assistance to hiring managers and maintaining excellent customer service throughout the selection process.
- Recruited viable candidates for different type of technical requirements and non-technical requirements.
- Developing and maintaining a network of contacts to help identify and source passive qualified candidates through online networking using "LinkedIn".

US IT Recruiter

VDart Inc March 2020 to June 2021

- A well-rounded result oriented individual with proven experience in areas of Recruitment/Account Management/ Client Management etc.
- Strong delivery and account management background with direct responsibility of fulfillment of requirements.
- Outstanding people management skills that includes ability to attract and retain talent.
- Excellent management skills, including the ability to motivate team members in a fast paced changing environment.
- Possess strong technical/business acumen and understanding of technical/functional requirements; deep sourcing skills; excellent candidate assessment skills.
- Possess excellent knowledge of recruiting and sourcing, preliminary interviewing, reference checking, rate/ salary negotiations.
- Have experience in dealing with all of kind of authorization (US Citizens, GC, EAD, HIB etc.) Hands on experience in contract, Permanent, Contract to Hire positions.
- · Short listing candidates according to the skills, experience, rate, location etc. Strong negotiation skills.
- Extensive experience in working with all kind of US and Canada based IT positions ranging from Developers to manager level positions
- Scheduling candidates for fact to face/telephonic interview events, establishing close contact with candidates to ensure participation in interview events.
- Extensive experience in job portals (i.e.: Monster.com, career Builder, Dice.com, Indeed, zip recruiter and LinkedIn, Etc.)
- Solid understanding of recruitment at all levels (technical & non-technical).
- A resourceful, solution-focused professional with excellent interpersonal and rapport-building skills.
- Management of the complete recruitment life-cycle for sourcing the best talent from diverse sources after identification of manpower requirements.
- Extensive hands on experience in various sourcing tactics such as cold calling, job boards, networking, etc. to ensure a diverse pipeline of candidates
- Self-motivated professional who achieves results and has superior ability to coordinate and perform several assignments simultaneously.
- Responsible for Key Account Management areas like Performance, Management and Growth.
- Set goals and manage the performance and development of whole team of recruiters.
- Creating recruiting metrics and recruiting team goals to drive results.

System Assistant

Big Data - Chennai, Tamil Nadu

June 2018 to December 2019

- I Systems Support Assistant assists in the installation, maintenance, and general support of systems. Assists users with questions or problems.
- Being a Systems Support Assistant may help perform system backups and recovery and install new software.
- May require an associate degree or its equivalent.